<?xml version="1.0"?>

  <document>

	<properties>
	  <title>Overview</title>
	</properties>

	<body>

	  <section name="Overview">

        <p>
          The GIANT project is about the development of a fast
          browsing tool for large graphs with enhanced analysis
          features like multiple selections and a fully integrated
          scripting language. The development team is 6 persons, all
          students of the University of Stuttgart, Germany. The
          project is part of our studies in Software Engineering.
        </p>

        <a href="http://www.bauhaus-stuttgart.de" target="_blank"><img
        src="images/logo_bauhaus.png" width="100" border="0"
        align="right"/></a>

        <p>
          The project was started in November 2002 and ran until
          November 2003. It was supervised by the <a
          href="http://www.iste.uni-stuttgart.de/ps/engl/index.html"
          target="_blank">Department of Programming Languages</a>. 
        </p>

        <p>
          GIANT was developed to display graphs that are used for
          reengineering purposes. These graphs are basically abstract
          syntax trees with lots of additional semantic
          information. The <a
          href="http://www.iste.uni-stuttgart.de/ps/bauhaus/index-english.html">Project
          Bauhaus</a> provides tools that can parse various
          programming languages and create a language independent
          representation called IML.
        </p>

        <p>
          The IML graphs are made availble through a reflection
          interface that is supported by GIANT. Even for small
          programms these graphs can have quite a large number of
          nodes and edges. In example a simple stack implementation
          written in C with 39 SLOC results in a graph of 223 nodes
          and 683 edges. The IML graph for the popular download tool
          wget contains more that 340,000 nodes and over 770,000 edges
          and occupies about 200 megabytes of memory!
        </p>

        <p>
          Besides the requirement to display large graphs the application
          was to be developed in Ada using GtkAda. Orginally GtkAda
          1.2.13 was used but later replaced by 2.2.0. Other tools
          that were used include AUnit and XMLAda. The GSL parser was
          generated by aflex and ayacc.
        </p>

        <p>
          For the development of GIANT a classical phase-model
          approache was choosen that worked out very well. During the
          course of the project important documentation like a
          specification and a manual were created.
        </p>

        <p>
          This page is meant as a project documentation and will
          hopefully be useful for other similar projects (like
          other Studienprojekte).
        </p>
	  </section>
  
	</body>
  </document>
  